moma.org 2017-05-25

# MoMA | Privacy & Security

# PRIVACY & SECURITY

  * [Senior Staff](/about/senior_staff)+
  * [Neighborhood](/about/neighborhood)+
  * [About This Site](/about/about_site)+

### RELATED LINKS

## MoMA is committed to protecting your privacy.

## Privacy

MoMA is committed to protecting your privacy when you visit our websites or use a MoMA application (collectively referred to as the “MoMA website”). MoMA does not collect personal information about individuals, such as names and mailing or e-mail addresses, unless the individual visiting the MoMA website knowingly provides it. By using the MoMA website, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of MoMA's Privacy Policy and Terms of Use. The MoMA Privacy Policy is outlined below. A link to this policy is provided in the footer information on every page of the MoMA website. Click here to view the [Terms of Use](/about/about_site/index).

## MoMA's policy on collecting information on the MoMA website

### Online Purchases

When you order a product from the MoMA Online Store, we need to know your name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information to process your order. Your credit card information will be stored temporarily on a secured server and used only as needed to process your transaction. We will retain your personally identifiable information for our records, in order to facilitate better customer service, and to inform you of our products and promotional offers. 

### Online Memberships and Donations

When you purchase a MoMA membership or make a donation to MoMA online, we will ask you to provide us with the information we need to process your membership and/or to acknowledge your contribution. This information includes your name, billing and mailing addresses, telephone number, e-mail address, and credit card information. Your credit card information will be stored temporarily on a secured server and used only as needed to process your transaction. We will retain your personally identifiable information for our records, in order to facilitate better customer service. To process payments for members who have selected automatic renewal, MoMA will also retain payment information, in a secure manner, until such time that either the payment information expires (when we will contact you to update it), or the auto-renewal of the membership is canceled by you. In certain cases, you may be asked for additional information to complete your request, such as the names and birth dates (month/year) of your children if obtaining a Family Membership or any Contributing Membership with children. See Children Twelve and Under.

### Registration

You may use the MoMA website without registering or submitting any personally identifiable information. [Registration](/login) for users and members on MoMA.org enables you to maintain your contact information and preferences, sign up for exclusive online features, purchase tickets more quickly, and receive notifications about events that interest you. You will be asked to provide personally identifiable information that may include a user name and password, your name, and an e-mail address. We store this information on a secure server so that you need not re-enter it when you return to the website. You may review or change your account information on the My Account page at any time.

### Online Surveys

From time to time, MoMA may invite you to participate in surveys posted on the MoMA website or sent to you by e-mail. You may decide whether or not you wish to complete such surveys, which may ask about your background, occupation, or similar questions. We use this information to help us better understand our audience, which in turn allows us to better meet your needs and interests. Information collected in these surveys is never sold, rented or shared with third parties for marketing purposes.

### Online Contests

MoMA will occasionally offer visitors the opportunity to participate in online contests or sweepstakes. If you choose to enter, you may need to provide your name and e-mail address so that we may contact you in connection with the contest. We may also request that you provide us with certain other information, such as your zip code, state of residence and grade in school (provided that you are at least thirteen years of age).

### Blogs

We welcome your participation on our blogs. An email address is required to post comments. We will not share these email addresses with any third parties for marketing purposes.

### Children Twelve and Under

MoMA does not solicit personal information from children. Visitors twelve years of age and under should remember that they are required to obtain an adult's permission before submitting any personal information to this or any other website.

### MoMA E-News

As a service, MoMA offers visitors to the MoMA website and MoMA Audio+ users the opportunity to subscribe to one or more of our online newsletters, a service hosted by a contractor that has agreed to use the e-mail address you provide only to send E-News to you. If you choose to subscribe, you will receive MoMA E-News on the topics you choose or, in the case of MoMA Audio+ users, general MoMA E-News. You may subscribe or unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions on the E-Newsletter.

### MoMA E-Cards

MoMA offers its online visitors the opportunity to send e-cards featuring works in the MoMA collection, in the MoMA Online Store or which are otherwise of interest. If you choose to use our e-card service, you will need to provide your name and e-mail address, as well as the recipient's name and e-mail address. E-cards will be stored for pickup for a period of thirty days. We will not share these e-mail addresses with any third party for marketing purposes.

### MoMA App

When you use the MoMA App, you will be given the opportunity to provide us with your e-mail address. If you choose to do so, we will send you an introductory MoMA welcome e-mail, and you will be subscribed to receive MoMA E-News, as described below.

### MoMA Audio+

When you use the MoMA Audio+ app (the “App”), you will be given the opportunity to provide us with your e-mail address. If you choose to do so, we will send you a link that will show you a road map of your visit, including the works you have viewed on the App and the photos you have taken while using the App, which you will be able to share with your friends. In order to use the share function on the App you will need to provide your name and e-mail address, as well as the recipient's name and e-mail address. We will not share these e-mail addresses with any third party for marketing purposes. In addition, if you choose to provide us with your e-mail address, we will send you an introductory MoMA welcome e-mail, and you will be subscribed to receive MoMA E-News, as described above. When you use the App to take photos during your visit, you understand that MoMA does not guarantee the quality or maintenance of your photos, and will not be responsible for photos that are lost, deleted or damaged for any reason.

### Emailing MoMA

If you email MoMA, your message and email address may be saved and we may send you emails in order to respond to your message. Any material, business information, ideas, concepts or other information sent to MoMA by email will be treated as non-confidential and non-proprietary. We will only use the information provided in your e-mail and your e-mail address to improve the MoMA website, services and products and to fulfill or respond to your requests for products, services or information. 

### Share Feature

MoMA uses third-party service providers to give you easy ways to share our content with others. The information you provide when using these tools is subject to the third parties’ privacy policies. 

### Cookies

Cookies are small files of information that are stored on your computer's hard drive by your Web browser. The cookies we use do not contain any personal information. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change the preferences of your browser so that it does not accept them. In order to use all the features of the MoMA website, we recommend that you accept cookies.

### MoMA's policy on the use and disclosure of the information it collects on the MoMA website and elsewhere

MoMA uses the personal information you provide to us for internal purposes, such as completing and tracking your transaction, analyzing trends and collecting statistics. MoMA may also compile and provide aggregate statistics about our visitors, customers, sales, traffic patterns and related site information to third parties, but these statistics will not include any personally identifying information.

We may share the names and postal addresses we receive from members and donors with other nonprofit organizations. If you do not want to have your information used in this way, you may send an e-mail message containing your name and postal address to [membership@moma.org](mailto:membership@moma.org). We may also share such information with third-party vendors who help us analyze and understand our donor and membership base.

After you make a purchase on the MoMA Online Store, we may share your name and postal address—but not your e-mail address—with other organizations or companies whose products might be of interest to you. The policies of these organizations and companies may differ from ours. If you do not want to have your information used in this way, you may send an e-mail message containing your name and postal address to [donotshare@moma.org](mailto:donotshare@moma.org). MoMA may release account information when such release is reasonably necessary to comply with the law; enforce the terms of any of our user agreements; or protect the rights, property, and safety of MoMA, the users of its site, or others.

If you have provided us with your e-mail address, we may send you e-mails in order to alert you to information, events, activities or programs at or related to MoMA that we believe may be of interest to you, or to alert you about sales or other promotional events at the MoMA Online Store. If you do not want us to use your e-mail address to contact you for these purposes, you may send an e-mail message containing your name and postal address to [donotcontact@moma.org](mailto:donotcontact@moma.org).

We may combine information you give to us online, in our stores or at the Museum or through our catalogs. We may also combine or supplement this information with publicly available information and additional information we receive from or have cross-referenced with our third-party vendors and others. We use this combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about products or events that may be of interest to you, or for other promotional purposes.

### Use of Outside Vendors

MoMA may from time to time retain qualified third-party vendors in order to help us manage the MoMA website and allow us to better serve our visitors and customers. These may include third-party vendors who assist us by processing registration and ticketing for certain events or courses. We also engage third party vendors to analyze the information we collect on the MoMA website for marketing or similar purposes. MoMA requires its vendors to maintain the security of the information to which they are provided access and restricts the vendors from using the information in any way not expressly authorized by MoMA.

We may contract with third parties who use cookies to collect information on our behalf. These parties are required to maintain the confidentiality of this information. If you would like to opt out of this use of your information, you can change the preferences of your browser so that it does not accept cookies. We may contract with companies or others to provide certain services, including credit card processing, data management, promotional services, etc. We provide these service providers with the information they need to perform these services, but we restrict the vendors from using the information in any way not expressly authorized by MoMA.

### Linking

The MoMA website may include links to websites operated by third parties over which we have no control. Once you leave the MoMA website, the MoMA Privacy Policy will not apply, and you access such sites at your own risk.

### Security

MoMA secure server software uses industry-standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology. SSL encodes your personal information, including credit card number, name, and address, as it travels over the Internet so that all transactions are secure. If you prefer, you may also place a MoMA Store order by phone at (800) 447-6662 or by fax at (212) 333-1127. For membership gifts, please call (888) 999-8861 and for donations, please call (212) 333-6591.

It is important for you to protect yourself against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. 

Be sure to use a known and trusted secure connection and to log off when finished using a shared computer. Notwithstanding our commitments to protect your information (including Personally Identifiable Information) from loss, misuse or alteration by third parties, you should be aware that there is always some risk involved in transmitting information over the Internet. There is also some risk that others could find a way to thwart our security systems. As a result, while we strive to protect your information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security and privacy of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. 

Please be advised that when placing an online order through the MoMA Online Store, your personal data will be protected in accordance with United States law but may not be at the same level of protection as is legally required in the European Union. 

### Revisions to our Privacy Policy

Please note that MoMA may revise its privacy policy at any time, without notice, such changes to be effective immediately upon posting on the MoMA website. Such revisions may arise in response to changes in the law, policy, or other factors. We encourage you to periodically visit this page to review our most current policy.

### Contact MoMA

Send your questions, comments, or concerns about our privacy policy or any other aspect of our website to [privacy@moma.org](mailto:privacy@moma.org).

Last update: July 22, 2015
